Guide to the Florence Ledyard Cross Kitchelt Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Florence Ledyard Cross Kitchelt papers
1920-1947
MS 315
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
9
The papers consist of correspondence, memoranda, printed material, and miscellanea relating to Florence Kitchelt's work on behalf of international peace, through the Connecticut League of Nations Association and the Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies, 1924-1945. Among the topics covered in the papers are Kitchelt's peace efforts in Connecticut, and related organizational goals, struggles, and activities. These papers document only Kitchelt's work in the peace movement and do not focus on many of her other social-political activities. The papers detail the levels of activity in several Connecticut towns and cities. As executive secretary of the Connecticut League of Nations Association, Kitchelt served as a source for information on regional activities.
Kitchelt, Florence Ledyard Cross, 1874-1961
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Florence Ledyard Cross Kitchelt in 1943, 1945-1948, and 1956; gift of Anna Donovan, 1986.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Arranged in three series. I. Connecticut League of Nations Association, 1924-1945. II. Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies, 1939-1942. III. Topical Files, 1920-1947.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, memoranda, printed material, and miscellanea relating to Kitchelt's work on behalf of international peace, through the Connecticut League of Nations Association and the Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies, 1924-45.
The papers document only Kitchelt's work in the peace movement and do not focus on many of her other socio-political activities. The papers detail the levels of activity in several Connecticut towns and cities. As executive secretary of the Connecticut League of Nations Association, Kitchelt served as a source for information on regional activities.
The Kitchelt Papers total seven and one-half linear feet (7.5') and are organized in twenty-five (25) boxes. The collection is arranged in three (3) series:
I. Connecticut League of Nations Association, 1924-1945
II. Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies, 1939-1942
III. Topical Files,1921-1947
Kitchelt selectively divided her papers by area of geographic and/or topical interest and donated these portions to various repositories. Other academic institutions with Kitchelt materials include Columbia University, Cornell University, Radcliffe College, and Smith College.
Biographical / Historical
Florence Ledyard Cross Kitchelt was born in Rochester, New York, on December 17, 1874 to Frederick Holland and Jennie Ledyard (Wilcox) Cross. She attended Wells College in Aurora, New York, graduating in 1897 with an A.B. Throughout her early career Kitchelt was a social reform worker at a number of settlement houses in New York City and state. Immediately after college Kitchelt was a resident and volunteer worker caring for dependent and delinquent youth at the George Junior Republic in Freeville New York. She spent the next four years working for the College Settlement on the lower east side of Manhattan and its summer location in Mount Ivy, New York. In 1903 she was the head worker of an Italian American settlement called the "Little Italy House" in Brooklyn, New York. For a short time in 1904 she was a voluntary probation officer for women at the reformist Essex Market Court. From 1904 to 1905 Kitchelt worked at the Lowell House in New Haven, Connecticut.
After spending several months in Italy learning about the conditions from which her many immigrant cases came, Kitchelt returned to her hometown of Rochester, New York. In 1907 she opened "The Housekeeping Center" in an Italian neighborhood there, and the center operated under her supervision until1910. In June 1911, she married New York socialist agitator Richard Kitchelt.
By 1915 Florence Kitchelt had become a suffragette, continuing her work when she moved to New Haven, Connecticut three years later. There she became the Citizenship Director of the Connecticut League of Women Voters in 1920, and served as the Executive Director of the Connecticut branch of the League of Nations Association (CLNA) for twenty years beginning in 1924. During 1943 she was Chairman of the Connecticut Committee for the Equal Rights Amendment, a group she supported until 1956 when she and her husband moved to Ohio to live with Florence's sister Dorothy Zeiger.
Kitchelt was also a dedicated peace activist and worked with a variety of organizations to pursue pacifist goals, including thethe Connecticut Council on International Relations, the National Council for the Prevention of War, and the Women's International League for Peace and Freedom.
Throughout her lifetime, Kitchelt was an active socialist, pacifist, member of the Unitarian society, and author of several books of poetry, a prose work called The World's Work, and editor for the Rochester magazine The Common Good. She died in Wilberforce, Ohio, on April 4, 1961.
International relations; Peace -- Societies, etc.; Peaceful change (International relations); Women and peace; Women; Connecticut -- Politics and government; New Haven (Conn.); United States -- Foreign relations; Angell, James Rowland, 1869-1949; Borchard, Edwin, 1884-1951; Danaher, John Anthony, 1899-; Fisher, Irving Norton, 1900-; Huntington, Ellsworth, 1876-1947; Taft, Horace Dutton, 1861-1943; America First Committee; Citizens for Victory; League of Nations Association of Connecticut; League of Nations -- Connecticut
- Connecticut League of Nations Association, 1924-1945; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Connecticut League of nations Association contains correspondence, printed material, and miscellanea relating to Kitchelt and her work as executive director of the Connecticut branch of the League of Nations Association (CLNA). Under Kitchelt's leadership, the CLNA operated a speaker's bureau, utilized radio stations to reach the public, circulated peace petitions, organized World Court Committees in several cities, and established local offices in towns and cities throughout Connecticut. CLNA publicity material, correspondence with activists and organizers throughout Connecticut, copies of petitions and speeches, and information on foreign military and peace activities are arranged in this series. These materials focus on the topic of the peace campaign in Connecticut, but also related to the broader questions of international relations, disarmament, war, and military policy. This series is alphabetically arranged by correspondent and/or topic, and is comprised of fourteen (14) boxes, and five (5.0) linear feet.
  - Branch newsletter, 1940-42 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bulgaria, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Canada, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cities
    - Andover-Bozrahville, 1926-41 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Branford, 1925-42, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Bridgeport, 1924-43, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Bristol, 1928-43, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Brookfield-Cromwell, 1924-43 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Danbury, 1926-39 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Danielson-Derby, 1928-41 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Durham, 1929-40 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Eastford-Ellington, 1926-43 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Enfield-Farmington, 1927-42 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Glastonbury-Granby, 1925-42 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Greenwich, 1927-41 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Groton-Guilford, 1926-43 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Haddam-Hampton, 1929-43 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Hartford, 1925-43 (Box 3, Folder 18 - 19)
    - Kent-Litchfield, 1924-44 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Madison-Meriden, 1925-41, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Middletown, 1924-40 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Milford-Naugatuck, 1926-42 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - New Britain, 1925-42 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - New Canaan, 1925-40 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - New Hartford, 1934, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - New London, 1928-42 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Norwalk, 1925-43 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Norwich, 1925-44, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Old Lyme-Orange, 1929-43 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Plainville-Pomfret, 1927-41 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Putnam-Ridgefield, 1925-43 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Saybrook-Stafford, 1926-43 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Stamford, 1929-38 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Stonington-Thomaston, 1928-41 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Waterbury, 1925-42 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Commission to Study the Organization of Peace, 1940, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 37 - 38)
  - Connecticut Council on International Relations, 1927-34 (Box 5, Folder 39 - 40)
  - Connecticut Peace Conference, 1938-39 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Connecticut State Conference Toward Victory, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1924-32 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Select, 1927-42 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Foreign, 1929-37 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Cuba, 1931-36 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Czechoslovakia, 1939-41, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Denmark, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Disarmament, 1928-35 (Box 6, Folder 49 - 50)
  - Disarmament: naval, 1928-30 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Disarmament Conference, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Domestic relations and petitions, 1924, 1929-32 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Educational programs, 1924-1930 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Educational Exchange material, 1909-34 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Emergency Peace Campaign, 1936-37 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - European Commission of the Danube, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - "Four Foreign Ladies", 1934 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Greece, 1925-35 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Institute of Public Affairs, 1936-40 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Institute on World Organization, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - International Peace Campaign, 1936-40 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - International Peace Congress, 1936-37 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Ireland, 1930-36 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Italy, 1943-44 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - League of Nations Association, 1925-44 (Box 7, Folder 66 - 68)
  - London Naval Conference, 1929-37 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Loyal Americans of German Descent, 1940, undated (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Mass meetings, 1934-38 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Membership book, 1935-45 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Membership lists, 1943-46 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - Miscellaneous, 1926-38 (Box 9, Folder 74 - 75)
  - Model Assembly
    - Yale University, 1927-30 (Box 9, Folder 76)
    - General, 1930-31 (Box 9, Folder 77)
    - Printed material, 1928-41 (Box 9, Folder 78)
    - Amherst and Mt. Holyoke, 1928-30 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Monroe Doctrine, 1918-33 (Box 9, Folder 80 - 81)
  - National Peace Conference, 1934-43 (Box 9, Folder 82 - 83)
  - New Haven Chapter, general, 1933-35 (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - Newspapers, 1924-35 (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - Pageants, 1937, undated (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - Palestine, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Panama, 1930-35 (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - Party platforms-pease, 1936, undated (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - Petition, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - Private manufacture of arms, 1934-35 (Box 10, Folder 91)
  - Programs, 1941-42 (Box 10, Folder 92)
  - Radio
    - Campaign, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 93)
    - Speeches, 1935-39 (Box 10, Folder 94)
    - WELI, 1936-38 (Box 10, Folder 95)
  - Refugees, 1934-36 (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - Russia, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 97)
  - Sanctions, 1932-38 (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Santo Domingo, 1930 (Box 10, Folder 99)
  - Security, 1924-37 (Box 10, Folder 100)
  - Smedley, Frederic C., 1936 (Box 10, Folder 101)
  - Spain, 1938-39 (Box 10, Folder 102)
  - Speakers, 1935-42 (Box 10, Folder 103 - 104)
  - Switzerland, 1932 (Box 11, Folder 105)
  - United Committee of South-Slavic Studies, 1945-46 (Box 11, Folder 106)
  - U.S. Department of State, 1929-38 (Box 11, Folder 107)
  - Upper Silesia, 1931 (Box 11, Folder 108)
  - War, 1929-37 (Box 11, Folder 109)
  - World Court
    - General, 1925-42 (Box 12, Folder 110 - 111)
    - American Foundation, 1925-34 (Box 12, Folder 112 - 113)
    - Cities
      - Bridgeport, 1925-30 (Box 12, Folder 114)
      - Hartford, 1925-32 (Box 12, Folder 115)
      - Meriden, 1925-31 (Box 12, Folder 116)
      - Middlebury, 1928-37 (Box 12, Folder 117)
      - Middletown, 1929-30 (Box 12, Folder 118)
      - Miscellaneous, 1925-41 (Box 12, Folder 119)
      - New Haven, 1925-41 (Box 12, Folder 120)
      - New London-Norfolk, 1925-37 (Box 12, Folder 121)
      - Waterbury, 1925-32 (Box 12, Folder 122)
    - Printed material, 1925-45 (Box 13, Folder 123 - 124)
    - Printed material and clippings, [ca.1924-25] (Box 13, Folder 125)
    - Gillet, Frederick H., 1928-30 (Box 13, Folder 126)
    - Senate resolutions, 1925-35 (Box 13, Folder 127)
    - Simonds-Steele, 1934-43 (Box 13, Folder 128)
    - Taft, Horace Dutton, 1938-42 (Box 13, Folder 129)
    - United States, 1925-31 (Box 14, Folder 130)
    - World Trade, 1930-38 (Box 14, Folder 131)
- Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies, 1939-1942; Series II
  Series II, Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies, 1939-1942, contains correspondence, printed material, clippings, and miscellanea concerning Kitchelt's work as head of the New Haven chapter of the Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies (CDAAA). Publicity materials, including press releases, telegrams, and printed material, detail the efforts to generate public support to the cause, while correspondence with numerous town and city chapters in Connecticut focuses on the organizational and membership problems which confronted the CDAAA. Topical files in this series include small quantities of information on such related organizations as the America First Committee, the Associated League for a Declared War, the Fight for Freedom Committee, and the Citizens for Victory Committee.
  This series contains three (3) boxes, or one linear foot (1.0') of material arranged in three sections: Office files, Topical files, and Citizens for Victory. Each section is arranged alphabetically by correspondent and/or topic.
  - Office files
    - Bulletins, 1940-1941 (Box 15, Folder 132 - 133)
    - Clippings, [ca. 1941] (Box 15, Folder 134)
    - Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 15, Folder 135 - 137)
    - Membership lists and miscellanea, 1940-1941 (Box 15, Folder 138)
    - Office memos, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 139)
    - Printed material
      - Miscellaneous, 1939-41, undated (Box 15, Folder 140 - 141)
      - U.S. government, 1940-1941 (Box 15, Folder 142 - 143)
    - Publicity releases, 1940-1941 (Box 15, Folder 144)
    - Telegrams and press releases, 1941, undated (Box 15, Folder 145)
  - Topical files
    - America First Committee, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 146)
    - Associated Leagues for a Declared War, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 147)
    - Connecticut Chapter
      - General, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 148)
      - Annual meeting, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 149)
      - Batterson, Walter E., 1940 (Box 16, Folder 150)
      - Origins, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 151)
    - City Chapters
      - Branford, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 152)
      - Bridgeport, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 153)
      - Hartford, 1940-1941 (Box 16, Folder 154)
      - Miscellaneous Chapters, B-W, 1940-1941 (Box 16, Folder 155)
      - Newton Chapter, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 156)
      - New Canaan Chapter, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 157)
      - New Haven Chapter
        - General, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 158)
        - Bailey, Harold C., 1941 (Box 16, Folder 159)
        - Danaher, John, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 160)
        - Finances, 1940-1942 (Box 16, Folder 161)
        - Freedom Rally, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 162)
        - Labor Division, 1940-41, undated (Box 16, Folder 163)
        - Meeting, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 164)
        - Minutes, 1940-1941 (Box 16, Folder 165)
        - Miscellaneous, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 166)
        - Petitions, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 167)
        - Questionnaire, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 168 - 169)
        - S, 1940-1941 (Box 17, Folder 170)
        - YWCA Speech, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 171)
      - New London Chapter, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 172)
      - Waterbury Chapter, 1940, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 173)
      - Westport Chapter, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 174)
    - Eichelberger, Clark, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 175)
    - Fight for Freedom Committee, 1941, undated (Box 17, Folder 176)
    - Japan, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 177)
    - Mass meeting, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 178)
    - Motion pictures, 1941 (Box 17)
    - Namesake Towns Committee, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 179)
  - Citizens for Victory
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 180)
    - Minutes, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 181)
- Topical Files, 1920-1947; Series III
  Series III, Topical Files, 1921-1947, contains clippings and miscellanea relating to several individuals, organizations, and topics of interest to Kitchelt. Individuals and organizations active in the peace movement, or having a great impact upon the movement, represented in this series include: Clark M. Eichelberger, Irving Fisher, Cordell Hull, Harold Laski, Charles Lindbergh, Horace Dutton Taft, Henry A. Wallace, the Connecticut Peace Conference, and the World Peace Foundation.
  This series contains eight (8) boxes, or one and a half linear feet (1.5'), and is arranged alphabetically by individual or topic.
  - Agor, Herbert, 1941-47 (Box 18, Folder 182)
  - American Legion, 1925-40, undated (Box 18, Folder 183)
  - Angell, J.R., 1930-42, undated (Box 18, Folder 184)
  - Angell, Sir Norman, 1936-42, undated (Box 18, Folder 185)
  - Bakke, Edward Wight, 1937-46, undated (Box 18, Folder 186)
  - Boudreau, Dr. Frank G., 1936-40 (Box 18, Folder 187)
  - Borchard, Edwin, 1935 (Box 18, Folder 188)
  - Briand, Aristide, 1931, undated (Box 18, Folder 189)
  - Bullitt, William C., 1941, undated (Box 18, Folder 190)
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1927-42, undated (Box 18, Folder 191)
  - Cecil, Viscount Robert, 1937-41, undated (Box 18, Folder 192)
  - Chamber of Commerce (National and International), 1929, undated (Box 18, Folder 193)
  - Churches, 1935-42, undated (Box 18, Folder 194)
  - Churchill, Winston, undated (Box 18, Folder 195)
  - Cohn, David L., 1937, 1939 (Box 18, Folder 196)
  - Colcord, Samuel (also Comstock, A. Barr, n.d.), 1929, undated (Box 18, Folder 197)
  - Conant, James Bryant, 1940-41, undated (Box 18, Folder 198)
  - Condliffe, John Bell, 1935, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 199)
  - Connecticut League of Nations Association, 1930-43, undated (Box 18, Folder 200)
  - Connecticut Peace Conference, 1932-40, undated (Box 18, Folder 201)
  - Coudert, Frederic R., 1931, 1933 (Box 19, Folder 202)
  - Crowdy, Dame Rachel, undated (Box 19, Folder 203)
  - Culbertson, Ely, 1942 (Box 19, Folder 204)
  - Cummings, Homer S., 1921-41, undated (Box 19, Folder 205)
  - Curtius, Julius, undated (Box 19, Folder 206)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution, 1927-34 (Box 19, Folder 207)
  - Darre, Richard Walter, undated (Box 19, Folder 208)
  - Davis, Malcom W., 1941, undated (Box 19, Folder 209)
  - Davis, Norman, 1946, undated (Box 19, Folder 210)
  - Dean, Vera M. (Box 19, Folder 210)
  - Dell, Robert (Box 19, Folder 210)
  - DeLanux, Pierre, 1935-38, undated (Box 19, Folder 211)
  - Dodd, William E., 1934-38 (Box 19, Folder 212)
  - Dolivet, Louis, undated (Box 19, Folder 213)
  - Dulles, John Foster, 1939, 1942 (Box 19, Folder 214)
  - Eagleton, Clyde, 1930-40 (Box 19, Folder 215)
  - Eddy, Sherwood, undated (Box 19, Folder 216)
  - Eden, Anthony, 1938, undated (Box 19, Folder 217)
  - Education by radio, 1932-39, undated (Box 19, Folder 218)
  - Education - general, 1924-29 (Box 19, Folder 219)
  - Educational books, 1924-36, undated (Box 19, Folder 220)
  - Eichelberg, Clark M., 1937-44, undated (Box 19, Folder 221)
  - Einstein, Albert, 1931-40 (Box 19, Folder 222)
  - Fenwick, Charles G., 1937, 1940, undated (Box 20, Folder 223)
  - Fisher, Irving, 1937-44, undated (Box 20, Folder 224)
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1929-37 (Box 20, Folder 225)
  - Fosdick, Harry Emerson, 1925-37, undated (Box 20, Folder 226)
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. (Box 20, Folder 226)
  - Gerig, Benjamin, 1939-41, undated (Box 20, Folder 227)
  - Green, James Frederick, 1934 (Box 20, Folder 228)
  - Haile, Pennington, 1936-42, undated (Box 20, Folder 229)
  - Hambro, Carl J., 1940, undated (Box 20, Folder 230)
  - Hartley, Livingston, 1940, undated (Box 20, Folder 231)
  - Hearst, William Randolph, 1934-38, undated (Box 20, Folder 232)
  - Hecksher, August, II, 1941 (Box 20, Folder 233)
  - Hendel, Charles W., undated (Box 20, Folder 234)
  - Holborn, Louise W., 1939, undated (Box 20, Folder 235)
  - Holborn, Hajo (Box 20, Folder 235)
  - Hudson, Manley O., 1925, 1937, undated (Box 20, Folder 236)
  - Hull, Cordell, 1929-44, undated (Box 20, Folder 237)
  - Huntington, Ellsworth, 1944, undated (Box 20, Folder 238)
  - Inman, Samuel Guy, undated (Box 20, Folder 239)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1929-30, undated (Box 20, Folder 240)
  - Institutes (International), 1926-39, undated (Box 20, Folder 241)
  - Jackh, Ernst, 1926, undated (Box 21, Folder 242)
  - James, Edwin L., 1942, undated (Box 21, Folder 243)
  - Jessup, Philip C., undated (Box 21, Folder 244)
  - Jews and Christians, 1935-39, undated (Box 21, Folder 245)
  - Knollenburg, Bernard, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 246)
  - Kohn, Hans, 1942, undated (Box 21, Folder 247)
  - Koppleman, Harman I., 1936-42 (Box 21, Folder 248)
  - Laski, Harold, 1940-42, undated (Box 21, Folder 249)
  - Latourette, Kenneth S., 1935 (Box 21, Folder 250)
  - League of Nations Association
    - Correspondence, 1934, 1936-38, 1940, 1943, undated (Box 21, Folder 251 - 252)
    - Branches, 1926-39, undated (Box 21, Folder 253)
  - League of Nations Union, English, 1929-37, undated (Box 21, Folder 254)
  - Lindbergh, Charles, 1927-41, undated (Box 21, Folder 255)
  - Madariaga, Salvador de, 1928-37, undated (Box 21, Folder 256)
  - Mathews, Basil, undated (Box 21, Folder 257)
  - Militarism in education, 1940, undated (Box 21, Folder 258)
  - Miller, Spencer, undated (Box 21, Folder 259)
  - Minutes, 1929-43 (Box 21, Folder 260)
  - Miscellaneous materials, 1930-44, undated (Box 21, Folder 261)
  - Morgan, Laura Puffer, 1935-36, undated (Box 22, Folder 262)
  - Morris, Charles G., 1939, 1943 (Box 22, Folder 263)
  - Motion Picture: "Hell and the Way Out", 1926-27, undated (Box 22, Folder 264)
  - Neilson, William Allan, 1932 (Box 22, Folder 265)
  - "The New Commonwealth", 1934-39, undated (Box 22, Folder 266)
  - New Haven Peace Conference, 1930-39, undated (Box 22, Folder 267)
  - Newspaper articles, 1929-33, undated (Box 22, Folder 268)
  - O'Ryan, John F., 1937-38, undated (Box 22, Folder 269)
  - Pageants and parades, 1927-40, undated (Box 22, Folder 270)
  - Peace ploys, 1928-37, undated (Box 22, Folder 271 - 272)
  - Perry, Ralph Barton, 1941-43, undated (Box 22, Folder 273)
  - Pope, James P., 1934-35 (Box 23, Folder 274)
  - Posters, 1920-39, undated (Box 23, Folder 275)
  - Publicity from Edgar J. Fisher, 1934-38, undated (Box 23, Folder 276)
  - Radio
    - Addresses-WICC
      - Auspices Connecticut League of Nations Association, 1935-36, undated (Box 23, Folder 277)
    - Correspondence, 1935-36, undated (Box 23, Folder 278)
    - Programs and publicity, 1937-40, undated (Box 23, Folder 279)
    - Programs-WICC, 1936, undated (Box 23, Folder 280)
    - WELI, 1936, undated (Box 23, Folder 281)
  - Robinson, Leland Rex, 1937-38, undated (Box 23, Folder 282)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1933-41, undated (Box 23, Folder 283)
  - Salter, Arthur, 1925, 1931, undated (Box 23, Folder 284)
  - Schuman, Frederick L., 1938-42, undated (Box 23, Folder 285)
  - Schwimmer, Rosika, 1937, undated (Box 23, Folder 286)
  - Seymour, Charles, 1937-45 (Box 23, Folder 287)
  - Sherwood, Robert E., 1940 (Box 23, Folder 288)
  - Shotwell, James T., 1925-45, undated (Box 23, Folder 289)
  - Smuts, Jan Christian, 1928, 1935 (Box 23, Folder 290)
  - Speakers
    - Herbert B. Ames, Frank Speer Coan, 1934, 1937 (Box 24, Folder 291)
    - Connecticut, 1924-42, undated (Box 24, Folder 292)